This is a $1.3 million luxury listing in
Belton, Texas. Or you could get this
house in Belton, Texas on the west side
of I35, priced at $315,000.
[Music]
really great comparison today because
you have that drastic difference in
price point. Both homes are in Belton
ISD. Very similar uh distances to Austin
Fort Kavazos. This one's a little bit
closer to Fort Kavazos and Waco,
Texas. So, this home is a
$315,000 house. Four bed, two baths,
just under 2,000 square feet. Brand new
construction by Tippet Homes. This
community is really growing. It's in the
Three Creeks community, so you are just
minutes away from Stillhouse Lake and
one of the only communities with walking
trails. So, that's really neat. But
before I go ahead and take you back to
that beautiful million-doll listing,
we'll take a really good tour of this
one. So, this is the
kitchen. It has some stone countertops,
which kind of looks like leathered
granite, but it's not. And then you
actually have three tone cabinets here.
You have white uppers, this wood color
lowers, and um some green cabinets in
the island. And everything is really
modernized here. Really pretty
selections, I think, for this price
point. really nice fixtures. So, you
have these beautiful gold brass uh
pendants hanging over your island and
then uh just really pretty fixtures and
pendants throughout which I'll show you.
You have this blond colored luxury vinyl
plank which I think is super popular
right now. You'll notice a very open
concept floor plan. So, your living
space flowing into your dining room.
really awesome kitchen, all very much
connected. Uh so you can be close to
everyone or just yourself if you just
like being solo. You have
a technically they're listing it as a
bedroom. It's set up more for an office.
You have your French
doors, but you do have a closet, which
makes it that uh extra bedroom, so to
speak. But lots of lighting throughout
this home. This builder did include
blinds, which is something not all
builders. Semi-split floor plan. On this
side of the house, you have your laundry
room, little prep area, some pretty
white cabinets and hardware that leads
into your garage. And so, come straight
through the garage to offload, you know,
your groceries into the kitchen. You
have the luxury vinyl plank in all the
main living spaces and carpet in the
other bedrooms. So that first bedroom
that's set up as an office that does
have your vinyl plank, but pretty
standard sized bedrooms, decent size
room, decent little closets. You have
that they they really carry through the
design elements through the bathrooms as
well. So, that same colored granite
countertop, vertical tile in the
bathroom, white
cabinets. This is that final bedroom.
So, it's pretty gloomy outside. I won't
show you too much out there. We can peek
in the backyard, but it is a little
overcast and unfortunately the builder
doesn't have uh with all the rain, the
grass is a little grown, so you'll just
have to picture that beautiful and
immaculate, which they would do for you.
Let's head on over to the master. Oh, so
the master does have the vinyl plank
throughout it. I like that feature. You
have your tray ceilings in here with
your recess lighting, so it just makes
it feel extra big and kind of elegant. A
nice little touch. And in our primary
suite, you have dual
vanity. You have that wood like
cabinetry in here. No tub, but a really
great sized walk-in shower with a little
seated nook. One of my favorite features
is how they laid this out. You have two
closets. So, you have, you know, his and
hers or hers and hers. Again, one of the
things I really love about this
community is that they are still
building. And so, a lot of these
builders are really wanting to offload
their
inventory. And they're currently
offering really, really great
incentives. Um, again, those are always
changing, but for example, I know this
builder is basically offering a large
amount towards closing costs, which you
can use to buy down your rate, pay all
your closing costs, things of that
nature. So, you have Dr. Horton in this
community still building. Uh, let's see.
Dear Horton, this one's a tip at home. I
think Stylecraft is in here. And then
Kathers is, you know, our luxury builder
in the area. They're building in this
community as well. I know at one point
Omega was I'm not sure if they currently
have any inventory, but the because this
community has been around for a little
bit, you have some resale homes that are
trying to compete with the new
construction. And then again, the new
construction just has so much inventory
that they're trying to offload. So, you
can really, really get a sweet deal in
this community. at about an hour north
of Austin, Texas, 45 minutes south of
WGO, Texas, and a good 20 minutes from
Fort Cavazo. So, this is a really big
area of interest for people working at
the hospital in Temple or those working
at uh you know, stationed at Fort K
working at Fort Kabazos.
Um, so really great comparison between
these two properties. Just kind of
depending on what area you want to be in
and which price point you're in. I'm
really curious to see your thoughts.
Which one did you like better? Um, and
also maybe which home, you know, are you
currently closer to? Are you currently
kind of closer to that starter home or
are you ready to move on up into that
luxury listing? Let's head on over to
our $1.3 million house in Belton, Texas.
This luxury listing was built in
2021 and it's in the Honey Glenn Acres
community in Belton, Texas, right off of
FM436 on the east side of I35. You're
still about an hour north of Austin,
Texas, 45 minutes south of Waco, Texas,
and about 25 minutes from Fort Kavazos.
This home is so gorgeous. It's actually
one of my favorite listings I've ever
shown. And in fact, I recently did a
video comparing three luxury listings in
Belton, Texas if you want to watch that
one next to compare this to some of
those. But this home is on 1.3 acres.
It's a five bed, 4 and 1/2 bath home,
just shy of 4,000 square ft. So really
great comparison to the last house in
terms of price, almost double the size,
huge lot. Uh, you also get a
1.5 tax rate here, whereas the last one
is 2.3. So, you'll save hundreds a month
in those monthly tax payments. But, uh,
this one's really gorgeous. I can't wait
to show you. Let's
[Music]
go. As we come inside, you can just
really feel how open this floor plan is.
Even though it's really gloomy outside,
there's still tons of natural light in
here. You have the really beautiful
vated ceilings which just make it feel
extra warm and inviting. Florida to
ceiling stone fireplace. Um it's staged
really nicely here so you can get a
really great idea of how your furniture
could sit and lay out. So, from our
entryway,
um, you get a little sneak peek of this
amazing backyard, which I'll show you
last. You do get that awesome pool for
those hot Texas days. The main living
space, kitchen, and dining space are all
connected. Incredibly open floor plan.
Um, it was built in 2021, but it
honestly feels brand new. Uh, you there
some similarities to the last. You have
that blond colored luxury vinyl
plank, those gold toned fixtures
throughout the home. I really love all
of their lighting. I'm weird about
lighting. I really noticed those things.
But kind of bird cage like nest, I don't
know, uh, pendants over the dining
table. I think look really funky and
cool. Wood burning fireplace, which is
really nice. You You probably won't use
it very often. A lot of people want
those fireplaces in Texas and then never
end up using them except for those
one-off chances that we have those big
freezes and you need them, which happens
like once every 10 years. Um, but my
favorite part is really this
kitchen. They did a fantastic job. You
have uh granite countertop in the
center, quartz counter accents uh on all
of the other counters, your uh kind of
honey colored, honey oak colored
cabinets. Again, really beautiful
fixtures. Something for all of my fellow
West Coastons, uh is this gas range. A
lot of people want gas when they come
here, but actually most of our
communities don't have it. So natural
gas or propane is actually hard to come
by. So you have this beautiful uh
stainless steel range, your pot filler
for all you kitchen
enthusiasts. Um you have your microwave
built into the island. That's kind of a
new feature that they're rolling out is
having that built into the island. You
have technically two sinks. You have
this sink overlooking your beautiful
backyard and
farmland. It's really interesting cuz
we're actually 20 minutes 15 minutes
from our last listing, but you really
get more of a rural farm feel out here,
more private. And then if we head over
to this side, we're going to do a little
loop around walk through of the
home. You might be wondering, where's my
pantry? Well, this is it. So, inside of
these farm doors, you have a butler's
pantry, uh, which kind of serves as an
extra prep area with another sink,
another space for a backup fridge, and
then all of your built-ins for your
pantry
items as well as an oven. And then back
down this way, you have a half
bath. You have a mud bench with your
hooks. So come in your your dirty kids,
spouses, whatever. They can kind of
strip down, throw their dirty clothes
into the laundry
room. Tons of prep um folding space,
counter space, and again another
sink. Appreciate that. Really funky tile
in some of these rooms, which is really
cool. Nice little accent.
upstairs. There's just a little loft
area, which is really neat with a nice
little
nook. Really functional space up here.
Game room, loft, uh, kid area, office
space. Can do a lot of a lot with this
um,
space. Cute little reading nook
overlooking your pool and sneak peek.
Little
basketball, little basketball/
volleyball court.
And then here you have a builtin desk
workspace area which is super cute, very
Harry Potter feel. And then you have two
of your guest bedrooms over here. No
carpet. Continues on that vinyl plank
throughout. Jack and Jill bathroom.
Awesome feature with their own separate
sinks and separate closet. So really
what you have shared here is your toilet
and shower tub
combo. Again, some funky
tile. Fun and and spicy in here, I
guess. All right, on this side of the
house, just a little
closet. Kind of like its own little
mother-in-law suite on suite, 10ft
ceilings. And then inside of the
bathroom, you have a really
great
shower, sink, and toilet. Full bath in
there. Okay, so we are in the master
bedroom. Again, overlooking that
fantastic backyard and 1.3 acre lot that
you have. Having that farmland behind
you makes it feel extra large to me.
You're kind of getting that view
extension.
[Music]
I think this is so pretty and such a
cool feature. You have a mirrored uh
sliding barn door into your master
bath. This bathroom is so pretty. Very
spaike. You have your freestanding
tub and your dual vanities along with
your really, really large shower.
[Music]
So, two closets, really great size
closet. Now, you see a lot of these
builders are starting to do that those
the gold fixtures, the brass. I'm kind
of curious. Do you do you like that? Do
you feel like that's phasing out? What
are your thoughts? Drop a comment below.
Okay. Well, I'm so excited to show you
this backyard. Um, again, if you want
more details on this or to compare it to
some of our other luxury listings, make
sure to watch that other
video. All right, let's step outside to
this dream
backyard. You can really just imagine
summers out here in Texas. It's a really
big deal and actually pretty desired to
have a pool. I know pools are a big
maintenance, but you'll really
appreciate it when we start hitting
those humid triple digits. Um, you have
a wonderful outdoor kitchen so that you
can grill your steaks, uh, hamburgers,
hot dogs, beautiful pool and spa with
your sports
court. And then you have this fantastic
pool house, which I think they are kind
of actually using as a maybe workout
studio or yoga studio. You know, you
have lots of options with that. Whether
you want to have a guest kind of tucked
away out here or your own little space
inside our little flex space has an
awesome separate uh bath. So, you can
use this as a pool bath. People that
come in here, use the restroom instead
of tracking their wet bodies
inside. Or you can, you know,
multi-purpose this, like I said, for
your own gym, office space, uh, or just
little guest house. But beautiful glass
doors again out to your fantastic
backyard. All right, so that wraps up
our comparison of our
$315,000 home in Belton, Texas, and our
1.3 luxury listing in Belton, Texas. I
hope you found it helpful. If you'd like
any more information on either of these
homes or just information on living in
central Texas, you can find all my
contact information below. Till next
time.
[Music]